gopal balachandra joining us CFO and
chief risk officer at IC Lombard lots to
talk about we saw premium degrowth in
Jan what's the Outlook now going forward
as well uh gopal thanks for joining us
now if we look at the product mix you've
nearly eliminated your exposure to crop
insurance talk to us about that shift
and elaborate on you know how you went
about this and
why sure I think uh good morning
everyone uh I think if you look at uh
the approach that uh icsl Lombard has
taken uh over the years uh it has always
been uh profitable growth as a theme and
that's something that we have continued
as a company for the last uh so many
years uh it is in that context that we
keep looking at uh product mix uh across
the organization it's not just about
whether it is crop or motor or health or
let's say any any of the commercial
lines across the portfolio of uh uh
businesses that we do we keep looking at
in terms of what uh environment does it
exist and in that context we take a view
on which are the segments which are our
preferred segments which we would want
to continue to ride growth in business
and certain segments which at a
particular point of time may not be
let's say viable in the context of the
profitable growth that we have as a
theme for the organization so in that
sense is the call that we we took in so
far as uh crop insurance is concerned
and by the way this is not the first
time that we are writing crop insurance
we have been commercially writing crop
since 2009 and that's a segment which uh
in under the current uh uh pricing uh
environment that exists and more
specifically the terms of reinsurance
that are available in the market uh
leads us to a situation where we are
cautious on that particular portfolio
and that's a call that we took at this
point of time given the current
terms of reinsurance that's available in
the market our mix of exposure to crop
for the current period pretty much
stands at uh zero relative to let's say
177% of the mix that we had last
year okay for the month of January the
premium reported a degrowth as well what
led to this uh you know if you could
share with us uh some of the factors for
the
trend sure um I think uh when you look
at our numbers again the numbers have to
be looked at in the context of uh as I
said uh we continue to look at as an
organization from an is Lumber
perspective uh areas of uh segments that
we are that are our preferred segments
now when you look at the aggregate
numbers what you're saying is absolutely
correct the growth overall possibly for
the month of January or even for the
matter of fact even if you were to look
at it on a 10-month basis the numbers
would look like possibly we are de
growing from the previous period as I
said in so far as our
uh approach to crop uh writing this year
we have been cautious is what I
mentioned earlier now if you look at the
growth of the business excluding the
crop portfolio our growth will look like
about 133% now that's on the aggregate
not just for the month of January even
if you were to look at on a 10-month
basis the growth in business would look
like X crop at about 133% but within
that the areas which are our preferred
segments of growth which is continues to
be let's say health motor and for for
for the matter of fact even commercial
lines they have all exhibited uh growth
rates which have been quite significant
is again an area which has been an area
of focus for ICC Lombard that segment
continues to witness a compounded growth
of 30% for the last 34 years uh retail
retail Health inunity again in segment
of focus for IC Lombard that's a segment
if you look at the new retail Health
inunity growth for the current again
10mon numbers if you were to look at
that has grown by about almost 90% plus
but that's primarily because we had a
relatively uh low base and that's a
segment which we have been focusing on a
lot in terms of opportunities for growth
commercial lines particularly when you
look at fire this year after let's say a
prolonged period of uh almost 10 years
of soft pricing for the market this is a
segment that I started to see
Improvement in pricing so that's again a
segment that we're growing quite uh
focused on and uh that has led to the
growth grow for Isis Lombard not just
for the month of January even if as I
said even if you look at it on a
10-month basis I think the growth has
been quite robust at about 13% X of crop
U you know there are also reports that
life insurance companies may be offering
inmy based Health policies how do you
view this and will it really bring in
higher competition in the
segment uh so I think again if you look
at health I think health is a segment
which is uh
health is a segment that is
significantly growing for the market and
that's a segment that we have seen uh
growth rates quite robust not just for
uh IC Lombard if you look at the overall
uh industry as well I think even for the
overall industry the growth in uh Health
portfolio has been robust uh
overall uh and um on a compounded basis
the segment has been growing in excess
of 20% uh year on year for the last so
many years and when you look at at
health I think primarily there are uh
three categories of uh customers that
you look at uh you have the uh retail
customers which is taking an uh
insurance for sale for their family
members you could have let's say the
corporates uh taking a coverage for
their employees and then you have let's
say the government sponsored Mass health
programs which let's say primarily
covers uh health insurance for the
largest section of the society despite
all of this uh coverages that exist in
the market if you look at the overall
pie that is covered getting covered
through insurance today it's just about
let's say uh the country's penetration
on uh insurance will be only in their uh
high 20s or maybe early 30s so that's a
proportion of uh the population that is
getting covered through Insurance in
some form of the other so that's one uh
in terms of the opportunity as I said
one is only onethird of the uh uh
population is covered through some form
of an insurance or the other and that's
primarily the hospitalization spends 2/3
of the healthcare spends of the country
that you see is out of pocket and at
this point of time that in that sense is
not necessarily covered in any form of
uh Insurance uh offerings that exist for
the market so that's a clear opportunity
and that's a direction that Isis Lombard
is taking I think while the
hospitalization insurance is something
that is an area of focus for us but we
are also looking at how we can also tap
on to the outof pocket spends which at
this point of time from a market
perspective and also with with respect
to an opportunity for IC Lombard we
clear clearly looking at that as a
segment for growth so in that sense even
while the regulator has set up a
committee to look into whether Health
Indemnity should also be offered by life
insurance companies our view is of
course we by the time we they announce
the results in April is the committee
has been given a time period of two two
months within which they would
definitely come out with their thought
process on what the views are with
respect to allowing a life insurance
company to offer uh Indemnity products
we will wait for for the outcome of the
committee but as I said the opportunity
for is Lombard is immense and that's an
area that we would continue to focus on
health is one of the preferred segments
of growth that's kind of continuously
growing well for the company okay good
to hear that and good luck with that
gopal good to have you on the show today